

# Summary of Qualifications

**Development Languages**: Java, C++, Python, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, XML **Tools and Platforms:** Android SDK, Android Studio, XCode, Eclipse IDE, Git, Bash, Unix

**Working On**: Data Science in Python, iOS development in Swift, SQL, Problem solving with algorithms and data structures

Experience with SCRUM and JIRA workflow environments.

## Experience

#### Lead Android Developer Mindbend Studio

Jun 2015 to Jun 2016

- -Lead Android developer in charge of planning for specifications, front end UI/UX design, wireframing, planning algorithmic operation to implement user flows, delegating tasks through SCRUM framework.
- -Formulated and worked on an original mobile application designed to digitize announcement systems in high schools.
- -Devised necessary back-end functions to drive data to and from front-end.
- -Investigated needs of end user group through close interaction with students and school administration; used this to incrementally improve app.
- -Pushed app to closed beta in local high school in early 2016.
- -Enhanced managerial skills by guiding a team of developers; improved time management by investing 10 hours per week while remaining a full time student.

#### Activities

#### Turner Fenton Software Dev Club Apr 2014 to Jun 2016

- -Co-founded club; taught fundamentals of programming and mobile app development to interested students at high school.
- -Developed management and leadership abilities as a result of creating weekly lessons and facilitating class discussions to ensure student success.

## **Education**

#### University of Waterloo

Candidate for Bachelor of Applied Science, Systems Design Engineering Sept 2016 - Present

-Achieved President's Scholarship of Distinction

Turner Fenton Secondary School International Baccalaureate Diploma Sept 2012 - Jun 2016

## Projects

#### Learning Lock Feb 2016

- -Hackathon project at SpartaHack 2016.
- -Designed wireframes and mockups, integrated unlock pattern library, pulled relevant data required by the neural network (ex. user drawn patterns, time between each node), optimized AI training by manipulating data input layers.
  -Produced Android lockscreen equipped with a neural network
- equipped with a neural network which can differentiate between the phone's owner and an intruder trying to unlock it to a high degree of success.
- -Worked with Android background services to create custom lock screen.
- -Selected as a DevPost weekly staff pick out of hundreds of projects spanning several hackathons.

#### Discoveo Aug 2015

- -Hackathon project at Tech Retreat 2016.
- -Geographical discovery app with a crowdsourced database of lesser known points of interest in the user's vicinity.
- -Implemented rating system for tagged points.
- -Integrated several APIs including Google Maps, designed data-driven portions of app.

#### ITGS Prep May 2015

- -Mobile app created to help students prepare for external IB exams.
- -Designed user flows and planned functionality of the Android app.
- -Wrote several back-end functions with Parse Cloud Code.